Elijah Owusu-Ewooral Boahen

github.com/ewooral | ewooral.com | info@ewooral.com | www.linkedin.com/in/boahenelijahowusu

SUMMARY

I'm a detailed-oriented, full-stack developer, with 4 years of hands-on experience, efficiently coding websites and applications using modern **Python, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, GraphQL and SQL** in tandem with famous frameworks like React JS, Plotly.JS, Django, Node JS,

MongoDB and others. Building state-of-the-art, easy-to-use, user-friendly websites and applications is truly a passion of mine. In addition to my knowledge base, I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IDADSTUDIO | Full-Stack ENGINEER (REMOTE)

Sep 2021 - Present | Hamburg, Germany

- Spearhead end to end web development using Python, Django, and React to build front-end architecture, back-end applications and user interface using iterative Scrum-based approach.
- Currently working on an Account manager App
 that solves a user-friendly issue (difficulty in
 navigating the client-side interface) pointed out by
 users of www.myfxbook.com platform. This App
 seeks to increase customer satisfaction rate by 50%.

PALM TREE, SOFT. | Full-Stack ENGINEER

Jan 2018 - Present | Accra - Tema, GH

- Cultivated expertise with cloud and web applications to build out server-side functions.
- Wrote code using Python and TypeScript on Django and React frameworks; leveraged familiarity with CSS and HTML to ensure seamless front-end content delivery.
- Leveraged knowledge of Agile XP practices to enable the build and integration of Lush View's new billing system, resulting in a 5% reduction in error rates.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF EAST LONDON

MASTER OF SCIENCE
MSC. COMPUTER SCIENCE
September 2021 | East London, UK
Still ongoing – Current

KWAME NKRUMAH UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY – KNUST

BSc. COMPUTER SCIENCE June 2017 | Kumasi, Ghana GPA: 3.03 / 4.0 Major GPA: 3.1 / 4.0

SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

Fluent in CSS, HTML, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, and Python.

Familiar with Dart, Java, Elixir, C, C++ and C# **Frameworks:** Fluent in React JS, Node JS, Django **Databases:** Familiar with MongoDB and MySQL

PROJECTS

JPMORGAN CHASE & CO

INTERN – JPMORGAN CHASE SOFTWARE ENGINEERING VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE | June 2020 – Sep 2021 | Virtual Experience.

- I worked on a **Trading analysis and stock price monitoring App** where I fixed the client-side web
 application so that it displays a graph that
 automatically updates as it gets data from the server
 application.
- I used perspective to generate a live graph that displayed the data feed in a clear and visually appealing way for traders to monitor this trading strategy.

ACCOUNT MANAGER APP

A PYTHON (DJANGO DOMINATED APP) | IDAD STUDIO – GERMANY.

- I worked on an account Manager App for Idadstudio, an app that renders client's details from Meta-Trader platform using Meta-API. This Project is still undergoing development.
- This project is analogous to <u>www.myfxbook.com</u> and seeks to solve a lack of user-friendly issue on the platform, outlined by users and make it easy for users to navigate the app without having to struggle.
- Languages used are Python, JavaScript in tandem with the Django framework.
- A Link to the project's directory can be found below https://github.com/Ewooral/Account-Manager

UPTIME MONITORING APP (RESTful API)

A NODE JS DOMINATED APP | PALM TREE, SOFT - GHANA.

- This API allows users to enter URLs they want monitored, and receive alerts when those resources go down or come back up.
- This API listens on a PORT and accept incoming HTTP requests for POST, GET, PUT, DELETE, and HEAD
- The API allows a user to sign in which gives them a token that they can use for subsequent authenticated requests.
- This project is ongoing. A Link to the project's directory can be found below https://github.com/Ewooral/RESTful-API-Uptime-Monitoring-App

Personal Projects

- Social Media App built with React and Node JS
- A personal Blog App built with React JS
- A Python API that includes features like, Authentication, CRUD operation, Schema validation, and Documentation.
- Real time Chat and Notification app using React and socket.io
- A modern Real Estate App with React and Rapid API
- Ecommerce App built with React, Node JS and MongoDB
- Basic CRM with **Django**.
- Video Chat App with React and WebRTC
- Cryptocurrency App with React and Redux